[Music]
hey everyone so I said I was done with
the London real story after our series
of films about their digital freedom
platform scam but I'm forced to return
to it because they have issued a
copyright claim got many of our
investigations taken down and also a
copyright strike against rebel wisdom
which is serious business because three
copyright strikes in your channel is
taken down the reason I'm making this
film is not just a capitalise on crying
censorship it's because it really
highlights all of the problems that I
was pointing to in the first series of
films which if you're not familiar with
the story I also wrote an article on
medium and linking to in the show notes
if you want to familiarize yourself but
effectively it was a story that
highlighted all of the problems with
free speech and censorship the
censorship decisions of the big tech
platforms but also how censorship itself
could be weaponized by bad actors you
know people who might do something like
I don't know raise a million dollars off
your followers under false pretenses and
then they'd all turn on you but the main
issue is that in that original film I
talked about how we the kind of wider
YouTube community people making content
had to become self policing otherwise
the big tech platforms would come and do
it and they would do it really badly
so the fact that this copyright system
can be weaponized and I'm going to
explain how it's been weaponized is a
really serious serious problem so we've
got this notification this morning a
copyright claim copyright strike and
video taken down click on it and sure
enough it's from London real TV and the
amazing thing is that it's this film
that they've done a copyright claim on
we did it over and over a million love
is the answer we must now prepare for
war and it's this particular part of the
film where Brian Rose talks about head
faking his audience so this is a quick
update the next day because a few more
copyright claims have come in so the
latest is the London real investigate
Update has been removed copyright claim
the original investigation has been
blocked copyright claim and so has the
update with coffee Zilla and rebel
wisdom but for about 24 hours the
original investigation was up with a
copyright claim but all of the ad
revenue was going to London real so
Brian I have donated the really
up thing about this is that copyright
law is designed so that this sort of
thing doesn't happen it always includes
a defense of fair dealing I know this
from working as a producer at channel 4
news for many years and I was very very
careful about the way I use this
material because I know the rules so
there's a few key things that you need
to do to make sure you have a fair
dealing defense one you have to label
the material clearly so you're not
trying to pass it off as your own which
I did with every single clip that I use
or very careful about that too you have
to use the minimum amount to make your
point you can't just use it as wallpaper
or b-roll but you can use it just to
illustrate the point that you're trying
to make or the criticism that you're
trying to make which I also did I also
tried contacting Brian Rose on multiple
occasions to get his response although
that's more of a defamation defense
rather than a copyright defense the
really up thing about this whole
situation is that the reason for using
this particular clip was because I was
making the point in multiple films that
Brian rose wasn't being honest with his
audience and in this clip he admitted it
he admitted that he'd been head faking
or being untruthful with his audience
this was the evidence that proves the
point that was being made and then the
person who makes that claim can use
copyright law to have it taken down now
the process from here as I understand it
is I need to object to the copyright
claim and then it goes back to Brian
Rose and London real who then have 30
days to decide whether it's a breach of
copyright or not and only after that
process some way down the line does you
get involved the whole point of fair
dealing is that you can do news
commentary of ongoing events and it
can't be used to evade scrutiny which is
basically what's happening here and of
course the massive irony is that Brian
Rose's digital freedom platform was
supposed to be all about free speech in
the first place so it's kind of ironic
that he's deleting a load of comments
from his site and issuing copyright
notices against people who are
criticizing him so we just want to play
a short clip from the first
investigation that I put out just
explaining what I think the bigger issue
is so the big picture framing I would
say is that we're in this kind of
interregnum period between two worlds
we've let the old gatekeepers are losing
their power increasingly fast but what
we don't have is you can imagine there
might be some kind of decentralized
Network way of coming to truth
democratic way of coming to truth that
could emerge on the other side we're not
there yet I think it's really important
that we use our free speech to call out
people who we think are being
irresponsible because right now if we
don't do this if we don't use our free
speech and somehow create some kind of
accountability then what's going to
happen is that the big tech platforms
are going to take those decisions for us
that we're gonna if we don't use free
speech with responsibility we're gonna
lose it in the first film I called the
whole situation a clusterfuck this is
another level of clusterfuck arried so
my whole point was that YouTube is
making editorial decisions without the
skill set to do it so what's the point
and how will this system become self
policing if YouTube's regulations mean
that bad actors can weaponize it so as I
said before I didn't really want to
return to the London real dumpster fire
and there were some signs of that who
the scrutiny was working not just rebel
wisdom but also coffee Zillow was
putting out a lot of films criticizing
Brian rose and looking at the things
that didn't quite add up and if you look
at the stats from London real it seems
to have had an effect and the audience
has turned in quite an amazing way if
you check some of the films for example
this one 425 down votes 104 up votes and
the comment
do speak for themselves it may be worth
reading off a few because they're
beautiful like I can't imagine a bigger
trainwreck with your audience because
basically he was getting all these
questions all this pressure and it's
like one day he just snapped like the
way he went after his audience was
insane
winners focus on winning see above
scammers this guy says scammers focus on
scamming and London ryoko's like you let
me guess you didn't donate here's
another one number one ask for money
Linden real money gets done fool
let me guess you're broke so let's
unpack that he's cursing at his audience
calling them fools that that may have
donated may have donated we don't know
in this case so at the same time as I'm
putting this up I'm also going to put
back up the interview that I did with
coffee Zilla while taking out the
copyrighted material that means it won't
get flagged again but this whole
situation really just highlights how
fragile the situation is for us content
providers on YouTube so if you're really
enjoying our content I'd bookmark a few
other places that you can find rebel
wisdom material so check out a podcast
channel leak details in the show notes
we're going to turn our website into
much more of a content platform as well
in the next few weeks or so also go to
the website and make sure you're on our
mailing list as well and we'll update
you about new films in that way as well
rebel wisdom was set up to make sense of
the world at a deeper level than the
mainstream media it was built for these
times of crisis and change which is why
we want to do what we can to meet the
challenge of the times more films and
also for our rebel wisdom members weekly
sense making calls with our amazing
interviewees and also we're introducing
the wisdom gym a place to practice some
of the skills that we've talked about on
the channel thanks for watching and see
you soon
[Music]